你好，你们这些漂亮的人知道你们什么时候在使用文件，什么时候在使用来自标准输出的数据
Hello you beautiful people know when you're using files or when you're using data from standard output
您很可能不想要所有数据，而是只想要其中的特定部分
it's very likely that you won't want all of the data but rather you just want a specific piece of it
你会想把所有的睡觉都切掉。
and you'll want to cut out all the rest.
现在，我们在Linux中这样做的方法是使用一个称为grep命令的命令。
Now the way that we do that in Linux is using a command called the grep command.
如果您曾经独自搜索过Linux，那么您可能只是在使用搜索引擎
And if you've ever searched about Linux on your own maybe just been you know using a search engine having
A环顾四周，你就会知道我已经遇到过这个团队，来吧，它是多么有用。
a look around you'll know that I've already come across the group come on just how useful it is.
在接下来的几个视频中，我们将向您展示如何使用grep命令搜索
So in the next few videos we're going to be showing you how you can use the grep command to search through
文件和标准输出，这样您就可以过滤输出对您来说很重要的数据。
files and standard output so that you can filter out just the data that is important to you.
在接下来的几个视频结束时，您将拥有一个非常强大的新工具，它将允许您
And by the end of the next few videos you're going have a very powerful new tool that will allow you
更快地做你想做的事，帮助你更快地在数据中找到东西。
to do what you want much faster help you find things in data much faster.
我们会帮你去掉很多你不想要的东西，这样你就能得到
And we help you cut out a lot of the fluff that you don't want so that you can get the results that
你想要的。
you want.
所以，让我们继续直截了当地谈吧。
So let's just go ahead and get right into it.
好的。
OK.
因此，作为快速提示，我想要讨论的第一件事是grep命令的实际作用。
So as a quick heads up the first thing I want to talk about is what the grep command actually does.
好的，在我们开始讨论它的工作原理之前。
OK before we start discussing how it works.
因此，GRIP命令将搜索您提供的任何输入，以查找包含特定片段的线
So the grip command will search whatever input you give it for lines that contain a particular piece
您告诉它要搜索的文本。
of text that you tell it to search for.
好的。
OK.
例如，我在桌面上有一个名为Haloed Optics的文件。
So for example I have a file here called haloed optics on our desktop.
如果我走到桌面上，使用cat命令来查看其中的内容。
And if I head over to the desktop and use the cat command to take a look at what's inside it.
令人惊讶的是，它说你好，还有漂亮的人，每个词都在自己的行上。
Surprise surprise it says hello there beautiful people with each word on its own line.
现在，让我们使用grep命令查找其中包含字母e的所有行。
Now let's use the grep command to find all the lines in there that contain the letter e.
好的，现在我们这样做的方式是，我们输入grep。
OK now the way that we do that is we would type grep.
那我们要找的就是。
Then what we're searching for.
所以字母A。
So the letter A.
然后我们要看的是什么。
And then what we're looking in.
所以我们会说你好，点文本。
So we'd say hello dot text.
好的，我们现在要说的是，嘿，grep查找Hello dot文本中包含该字母的每一行
Ok so here what we're saying is hey grep find every line in Hello dot text that contains the letter
e，现在默认情况下，grep命令区分大小写。
E and now by default the grep command is case sensitive.
所以大写和小写都很重要。
So uppercase and lowercase do matter.
好的，如果我按Enter键，您会在这里看到包含字母E和偶数的行
OK so if I press Enter you'll see here that we're seeing the lines that contain the letter E and even
信件本身也被强调了。
the letters themselves have also been highlighted.
所以这很酷。
So that's pretty cool.
有趣的是，在1939年，有一个叫欧内斯特·文森的人写了一本小说叫“盖茨比”。
Now interestingly in 1939 there was a person called Ernest Vinson right who wrote a novel called Gadsby
那大约有50000个字长。
that was about 50000 words long.
关于盖茨比的特别之处在于，尽管它有50000个字长。
Now the special thing about Gadsby was that even though it was 50000 words long.
他用的字母一次也没有，这并不令人难以置信，特别是如果你考虑到字母E是
Not once was the letter he used it was not incredible especially if you consider that the letter E is
显然是英语字母表中最常用的字母。
apparently the most commonly used letter in the English alphabet.
所以，不使用字母写一本50000字的书，就像写故事一样，这真的是一项相当大的成就
So that's really quite an achievement to write a 50000 word book like a story without using the letter
一个。
A.
我只是碰巧，我不知道这是怎么发生的，这里有一份Gadsby的拷贝，这是随机创建的
And I just so happen I don't know how this happened to have a copy of Gadsby here in this randomly created
我们桌面上名为Gadsby的文件夹就在这里，所以我们需要Gadsby手稿Dotti XTi。
folder on our desktop called Gadsby right here so we want Gadsby manuscript Dotti XTi.
现在这本书已经很旧了，它可以在公共领域免费获得，你可以访问
Now the book is so old now that it's freely available in the public domain and you can get access to
这与使用我将放入资源中的链接有关。
it to using the link that I'll put in the resources.
现在不管怎样，这样做的原因是我们可以使用on来计算某个特定的行数
Now Anyway the reason for this is that we can use the come on to count the number of lines a certain
出现一段文本。
piece of text appears.
好的。
OK.
例如，当我们在Hello 0.60中搜索字母E时，我们会得到四个正确的结果。
So for example we see that when we search for the letter E in Hello 0.60 we get four results right.
所以我们跟那些漂亮的人打招呼。
So we get hello there beautiful people.
好的。
OK.
所以我们实际上可以确认这一点，我们可以通过给予代表来C选项来查看一下，这将
So we can actually confirm this we can take a look by giving the rep come on the C option and this will
告诉你有多少行，它会给你找到的行数，它会告诉我们，我们
tell you how many lines it'll just give you the number of lines that it finds and it tells us that we
拿到四个。
get four.
好的。
OK.
所以它说，嘿，我在Hello T，S，T中找到了四行里面有字母E的行。
So it says hey I found four lines that had the letter E in them in Hello T S T.
现在我们有了名为Gadsby手稿Dottie XTi的文本文件。
Now we have the text file called Gadsby manuscript Dottie XTi.
好的。
OK.
如果我们打开它，你会看到这里有这么多东西。
And if we open it you can see that there is so much stuff in here.
好的。
OK.
这本书大约有43章长，超过50000字，实际上我可以告诉你是如何做到的
Is the fact the book is about 43 chapters long with over 50000 words and actually I can tell you how
通过进入Gadsby文件夹并在命令打开的情况下使用单词count，可以看到许多行
many lines is in there by going into the Gadsby folder and using the word count with the command on
盖茨比手稿告诉我们有1,914
the Gatsby manuscript and tells us that it tells us that there's one thousand nine hundred and fourteen
线条，这是相当多的线条。
lines which is quite a lot of lines.
好的，让我们试着在Gadsby一书中搜索Gadsby这个词，因为如果我在里面搜索GREP Gadsby
OK so let's try and search for the word Gadsby in the book Gadsby because if I do grep Gadsby inside
Gadsby手稿Dottie Xti你会注意到什么都没有出现。
Gadsby manuscript Dottie XTi you'll notice that nothing shows up.
没有显示的原因是因为Gadsby以大写G开头，而我们将其拼写为
And the reason that nothing shows up is because Gadsby starts with a capital G and we spelt it with
这里是小写的g。
a lowercase g here.
现在我们可以以不区分大小写的方式进行搜索。
Now we can search in a case insensitive manner.
因此，通过给组命令提供选项，大写和小写都无关紧要。
So the uppercase and lowercase don't matter at all by giving the group command the option.
好的，当我们这样做的时候，我们会看到它向我们展示了不同数量的结果，
OK so when we do that we'll see that it shown us it shown us a different amount of results here and
盖茨比在书中出现过好几次。
there's quite a few times that Gadsby has appeared in the book.
盖茨比的屏幕也一样清晰。
Gadsby has as clear the screen.
您也可以在Goldsby书中搜索字母A，只需将字母A放在这里，我们将
You can also search for the letter A in the Goldsby book just by putting the letter A here and we'll
注意，我们在使用字母A的地方有一整串行。
see that we get a whole bunch of lines where the letter A is used.
好的。
OK.
如果需要，我们也可以通过按C选项进行计数，我们看到这951行包含
And we can count that as well if we want by pressing the C option and we see this 951 lines that contain
那封信。
the letter.
所以这是相当多的。
So that's quite a lot.
现在我们来看看这本书用了多少次这个字母。
So now let's try and see how many times the book uses the letter.
好的，所以我们要做的是，我们不管它是大写的还是小写的，我们不需要任何e。
OK so that we do that is we don't care whether it's uppercase or lowercase we don't want any e's.
所以我们要让它不区分大小写。
So we're going to keep it case insensitive.
会不会算一下有多少条线。
And would it count how many lines there are.
我们要把后者放在那里。
And we're going to put there the latter.
如果我们现在继续按Enter，我们可以看到答案是零。
And if we go ahead now and press ENTER we can see that the answer is zero.
所以盖茨比的手稿没有使用字母E，这已经被Linux批准了
So the Gatsby manuscript doesn't use the letter E and this has been approved Linux approved that it
没有用到这封信。
doesn't use the letter.
因此，请下载参考资料部分的手稿，并亲自试用。
So download the manuscript in the resources section and try it out for yourself.
现在，您实际上还可以搜索完整的句子，只要您用引号将它们引起来。
Now you can actually also search for full sentences as long as you surround them in quotes.
书中有一句话说得很多，那就是我们的孩子们的台词，这样我们就可以在那里搜索
So one phrase that is quite a bit in the book is the is the line our boys so we could search in there
我们要用引号把它引起来，以确保它作为一个论点出现。
for boys and we're going to put that in quotes to make sure it goes in as one argument.
当我们按Enter键时，您可以看到包含它的那九行，但我们也来看一下
And when we press ENTER you can see those nine lines that contain it but let's just take a look as well
来查看它们，这样你就可以看到文本有相当多的结果。
to see them so you can see there's quite a few results for the text.
啊，孩子们。
Ah boys.
现在，您还可以搜索与特定文本不匹配的行。
Now you can also search for lines that don't match a specific piece of text.
好的。
OK.
这样，您就可以使用字数统计命令查看整个Gatsby文档中有多少行，如果
So you can see how many lines there are in the whole Gatsby document using the word count commands if
我现在做了一个1914行的破折号l Gad的B手稿，因为在Gadsby中没有字母E。
I do a word count dash l Gad's B manuscript in 1914 lines right now because there's no letter E in Gadsby.
应该有1914行不带字母H。
There should be 1914 lines without the letter H.
现在我们可以使用V选项进行检查。
Right now we can check that using the V option.
现在，v选项基本上执行相反的或反转搜索。
Now the v option basically does the opposite or invert the search.
好的，如果我们用带v选项的egrep进行grep。
OK so if we do grep with egrep with the v option for.
E A K in Gadsby手稿Dotti x t.
E A K in Gadsby manuscript Dotti x t.
我们所做的就是我们在努力。
What we're doing is we are trying.
这将找出所有没有字母E的行。
This is going to find all the lines that don't have the letter E in them.
就像我说的，如果没有V，您将找到所有包含e的行，而使用V选项，您将找到所有包含e的行
Like I said without the V you will find all the lines that do have e in them and with the v option you'll
找出所有没有字母V的行，让我们这样做。
find all the lines that don't have the letter V in them so let's do that.
所以我们看到一大堆东西都出来了。
So we saw a whole bunch of stuff has come out.
但是有多少人，有多少人真的出来了。
But how many of them how many of them have actually come out.
好的，我们可以用C选项来计算，我要上法庭了，我现在就把它剪掉。
Well we can count them using the C option and I'm going to court I'm going to cut it right now.
会不会是1914年的行会不会真的没有字母。
Will it be 1914 lines will Gadsby actually contain no letter.
哦，真是节省了时间啊。
Oh what a save on time.
请在下一个视频中回来了解。
Come back in the next video to find out.